Inventory of the Metallized Materials Company Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Metallized Materials Company Records
1972-1995
2001C88
Metallized Materials Company
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Contracts, agreements, protocols, minutes, and legal and financial records, relating to manufacture of metal products in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
British-German-Soviet joint venture company
Scope and Content of Collection
Contracts, agreements, protocols, minutes, and legal and financial records, relating to manufacture of metal products in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Metal products--Russia (Federation).; International business enterprises--Russia (Federation).
Collection Contents
- Supply contract, 1990 (Folder 1: 1)
- USSR protocol, December 1987 (Folder 1: 2)
- Ratified joint venture, 1988 (Folder 1: 3)
- USSR certificate of registration of joint venture with the Minister of Finance, 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- Joint venture agreement, articles of association, 1989-1990 (Folder 1: 5)
- Export contract, 1990 (Folder 1: 6)
- Export license, 1992 (Folder 1: 7)
- Joint venture agreement, 1990 (Folder 1: 8)
- Alucit Limited contract draft, undated (Folder 1: 9)
- USSR METMA seal, undated (Folder 1: 10)
- Prodicom non-disclosure agreements, 1988 (Folder 1: 11)
- USSR ministry of metallurgy approval for joint venture, 1988 (Folder 1: 12)
- Contracts, copy of bound book, 1989-1991 (Folder 1: 13)
- Legal U.S. license, 1992 (Folder 1: 14)
- Legal, FDA, 1992 (Folder 1: 15)
- Legal documentation, 1992-1993 (Folder 1: 16)
- Legal, Alusit Limited holdings assignment, 1994 (Folder 1: 17)
- Legal, stamp page and Russian document, 1992-1994 (Folder 1: 18)
- USSR, protocol memorandum, 1988 (Folder 1: 19)
- USSR, protocol memorandum of negotiations, 1988 (Folder 2: 1)
- USSR, protocol memorandum of meeting of representatives, 1988 (Folder 2: 2)
- Protocol addendum, 1990 (Folder 2: 3)
- USSR, protocol of meeting, 1990 (Folder 2: 4)
- USSR, protocol of meeting with Alusit, September 1991 (Folder 2: 5)
- USSR, protocol of consideration of contract fulfillment terms, June 1991 (Folder 2: 6)
- Technical protocol, Moscow, February 1991 (Folder 2: 7)
- Protocol, meeting of the board of directors, November 1992 (Folder 2: 8)
- USSR, protocol, minutes of the board of directors meeting, April 1992 (Folder 2: 9)
- Protocol of the board of directors meeting, July 1992 (Folder 2: 10)
- Protocol of meetings, July-October 1992 (Folder 2: 11)
- Protocol memorandums, March-December 1993 (Folder 2: 12)
- USDOC Russian economic and trade policy report, 1992 (Folder 2: 13)
- General articles and magazines, 1992 (Folder 2: 14)
- General brochures, articles, reports, 1991 (Folder 2: 15)
- General visa paperwork, 1993-1994 (Folder 2: 16)
- Noise level regulations, undated (Folder 2: 17)
- Safety and fire codes, 1972 (Folder 2: 18)
- Russian regulations, 1986-1990 (Folder 2: 19)
- Notes, undated (Folder 2: 20)
- Experimental plant product description, undated (Folder 2: 21)
- Description of the metallization and aluglas process, undated (Folder 2: 22)
- Joint venture feasibility study, 1988 (Folder 2: 23)
- Russian feasibility study, July 1992 (Folder 2: 24)
- Russian feasibility study, February 1990 (Folder 2: 25)
- Installation, 1990-1994 (Folder 2: 26)
- Invoices and payments, circa 1990-1994 (Folder 2: 27)
- Metalized paper test report, 1993 (Folder 3: 1)
- Project schedule, 1990 (Folder 3: 2)
- Yegor Gaidar correspondence, July 1992 (Folder 3: 3)
- Drawings, floor plan layouts, undated (Folder 3: 4)
- General installation photos, undated (Folder 3: 5)
- Minutes of board meeting, November 1995 (Folder 3: 6)
- Publicity article, September 1994 (Folder 3: 7)
- Schwarzmann visit, December 1992 (Folder 3: 8)
- Metalized samples for Aluprint analysis, undated (Folder 3: 9)
- Varnish contracts, 1995 (Folder 3: 10)
- Rotomec drawings, plans for Laminator/Delaminator, circa 1991 (Folder 3: 11)
- Rotomec drawings, plans for Delaminator web path, circa 1991 (Folder 3: 12)
- Rotomec drawings, plans for air purging of electrical Parts, 1992 (Folder 3: 13)
- Rotomec drawings, plans for exhaust and water cooling circuit, 1991 (Folder 3: 14)
- Rotomec drawings, plans for Delaminator fix, 1994 (Folder 3: 15)
- Equipment photos, undated (Folder 3: 16)
- Letters of credit correspondence, 1992 (Folder 3: 17)
- Correspondence regarding Yugoslav government, 1992 (Folder 3: 18)
- Banking, share capital contribution, Alusit/Becker, 1991 (Folder 3: 19)
- Alusit advance payment and down payment guarantee, undated (Folder 3: 20)
- Letters of credit, amendments, 1991 (Folder 3: 21)
- Letters of credit, installation and commissioning correspondence, 1992-1993 (Folder 3: 22)
- Banking and financing, letters of credit, 1991-1994 (Folder 3: 23)
- Banking and financing, loan agreements, 1993 (Folder 3: 24)
- Banking and financing, drafts, circa 1991-1994 (Folder 3: 25)
- Lee Miller sound recording on one compact sound cassette, 8 November 2001 (Folder 3)